Guide to the Ernie Durawa Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
Ernie Durawa Accessions
1958-2009
The Wittliff Collections https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu
Durawa, Ernie
UPWC.19043
5.5 Linear Feet
4 boxes
Multiple accessions from drummer Ernie Durawa document his decades-long performing with artists such as The Texas Tornados, Willie Nelson, Johnny Bush, Flaco Jimenez, and others. Included are awards, posters, photographs, and video cassettes.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ernie Durawa, 2009.
Biographical Note
Drummer Ernie Durawa was born in San Antonio and has performed on Grammy Award-winning recordings. He is perhaps best known for his work with the Texas Tornados (Freddy Fender, Flaco Jimenez, Augie Meyers, Doug Sahm.) In addition to his work with the Texas Tornados, Ernie Durawa has played with a number of prominent musicians: Willie Nelson, Townes Van Zandt, Delbert McClinton, Merle Haggard, Johnny Bush, Maryann Price, Floyd Domino, Doug Sahm, Flaco Jimenez, and many more.
Abstract
Multiple accessions from drummer Ernie Durawa document his decades-long performing with artists such as The Texas Tornados, Willie Nelson, Johnny Bush, Flaco Jimenez, and others. Included are awards, posters, photographs, and video cassettes.
Index Terms
Subjects
Musicians -- Texas
Subjects (Corporations)
Texas Tornados (Musical group)
- Accession 2009-043
  Abstract
  Various awards presented to Ernie Durawa.
  - Texas Tornados Texas Festival at the Kennedy Center, 1991 (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - Austin NARAS Committee for performance with Texas Tornados, 1991 (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - National Academy of Recording Arts & Sciences award for participation on the Grammy-Winning record "Flaco Jimenez" (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - National Academy of Recording Arts & Sciences award for Best Mexican/American Performance on Grammy winning record "Soy de San Luis" with the Texas Tornados (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - Award from the Governor of Texas Rick Perry presented to the Texas Tornados "For their musical contributions to the State of Texas", 2001 (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - Proclamation of "Ernie Durawa Day" in Austin, Texas, February 5, 2005 (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - "Drums Ernie Durawa, Los Jazz Vatos" presented by the Austin Music Awards, Austin Chronicle (framed), 2003-2004 (Box 1228, Folder 2)
  - "Jazz, Los Jazz Vatos" presented by the Austin Music Awards, Austin Chronicle (framed), 2003-2004 (Box 1228, Folder 3)
  - "Hall of Fame Ernie Durawa" presented by the Austin Music Awards, Austin Chronicle (framed), 2003-2004 (Box 1228, Folder 1)
  - "ICAP presents Ernie Durawa Two Time Grammy Award Winning and Texas Hall of Fame Drummer" (original and copy?) 16" x 12" (Box 1003, Folder 1)
- Accession 2009-070
  Additional awards, photographs, and some ephemera documenting Ernie Durawa's career.
  - Photograph by Dan Flores of the Texas Tornados; included in the photograph are Augie Myers, Doug Sahm, Freddy Fender, Flaco Jimenez, Durawa and two others 8" x 10" color photo (Box 1231, Item 1)
  - The front cover of "The Good Life" magazine, 10 1/2" x 14", featuring Durawa and others [not named], December 1997 (Box 1231, Item 1)
  - Resolution from the State of Michigan honoring Ernie Durawa and the Texas Tornados for their participation in the Michigan festival, 16" x 10 1/2", awarded by the Commission on Spanish Speaking Affairs (Box 1231, Item 1)
  - Poster "The Monstas/Meet the Monstas" [previously folded] 12" x 10" (Box 1231, Item 1)
  - Name badge with lanyard for the Fiesta Blues Heritage Series, Ernie Durawa performer, 2009 (Box 1231, Item 1)
  - Flyer for drum lessons given by Ernie Durawa and Aaron Lack 8" x 10" (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Certificate of appreciation from the Wesley UMC Intergenerational Choir awarded to Durawa, September 30, 2001 (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Community Legacy Award presented to Ernie Durawa and the Austin Jazz Workshop, May 10, 2000 (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Photograph of Durawa inscribed "To Ginger with all my love, Ernie" 8" x 10" black/white (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Photograph of the Elk Hearts combo, inscribed on back "To my dear Daddy from Neto at the age of 16 with the Elk Hearts Combo" 8" x 10" black/white in fragile condition with some small tears and creases. Stamped from the Diaz Studio San Antonio, Texas, December 24, 1958 (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Photograph identified by Durawa as the Delbert McClinton band along with McClinton's father 8" x 10" black/white, circa 1979 (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Photograph of Doug Sahm; it appears to be on cardstock and adhered to a matt [partially unglued] 8" x 10" black/white (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Photograph identified by Durawa as the Dellkings from San Antonio; Durawa is "the guy on the right in sunglasses" 8" x 10" black/white, circa late 1960s (Box 1232, Item 1)
  - Black wooden plaque "Idolos del Barrio Music Award" for Outstanding Contribution to Latino Music presented to Durawa by the Austin Latino Music Association, May 25, 2007 (Box 1232, Item 2)
  - Wooden plaque "Gram Award Group of the Year Award The Texas Tornados" presented by the DCMA & Country Gazette, 1992 (Box 1232, Item 3)
  - Wood plaque "The Jiveman Award" presented to Durawa for contribution to music and for dedication to group "Charlie and the Jives" by Charlie Alvarado, February 29, 2004 (Box 1232, Item 4)
- Accession 2009-075
  Addition to the Durawa Accessions contains seven VHS tapes, limited ephemera and one unopened album "Jammn' with J. R. and Friends"
  - Set list for a Texas Tornados performance, undated (Box 1231, Folder 2)
  - International Musician" magazine which includes a photograph and paragraph on Durawa donating material to the Wittliff Collections, page 9, April 2009 (Box 1231, Folder 2)
  - Poster for overseas festival featuring Durawa [small tear on right side] [16" x 12"] (Box 1231, Folder 2)
  - Unopened album "Jammn' with J. R. and Friends" (Box 1231, Folder 2)
  - "Texas Tornados - Inaugural Ball" [DVD transferred from VHS] (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - "Texas Tornados - Montreux Jazz Festival" [DVD transferred from VHS] (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - "Doug & Ernie Sweden"[DVD transferred from VHS] (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - "Country Heart" [DVD transferred from VHS] (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - "El Paso Herald-Post" newspaper review, March 1991 (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - "The Tornado Band" photograph [8" x 10"' color (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - unidentified color photograph [4" x 6"] (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - Photograph that includes Durawa and Doug Sahm [worn and fragile condition] [5" x 7"] (Box 1232, Folder 2)
  - "Doug and Ernie Sweden plus 90 min more!" (Box 1232)
  - Maxell 120 HG VHS, not titled (Box 1232)
  - "Quincy Jones presents the Montreux Jazz Festival The Texas Tornados 1:51:39" (Box 1232)
  - "Ernie Durawa "Inaugural Ball - Texas Tornados 1-20-93", January 20, 1993 (Box 1232)
  - "Freddy Fender 'Blanca Navidad' Arista/Texas" (Box 1232)
  - "Texas Tornados Is Anyone Going to San Antone? La Mucura 2:36" (Box 1232)
  - "Texas Tornados 'Rosa de Amor' 3:11" (Box 1232)
- Accession 2009-124
  Additions to the Ernie Durawa collection includes photographs and VHS tapes relating to Ernie Durawa and the Texas Tornados.
  - Three 8" x10" color photographs of Durawa and two 8" x 10" color photographs (Box 1252, Folder 1)
  - Itineraries from the Texas Tornadoes, removed from a blue binder labeled "Texas Tornadoes Ernie Durawa" (Box 1252, Folder 1)
  - VHS Cassettes
    - Refugee Management Texas Tornadoes 1. MTV news 2. Adios Mexico 3. Sir Douglas Quintet 9:30 Dub from VHS, March 8, 1991 (Box 1252)
    - The Dennis Miller Show #D0505-92 length 58:40 mins. 5/6/92 D188409 Brillstein-Grey Productions viewing cassette, 1992 (Box 1252)
    - TX Dept. of Hwys. & Transportation "Tx Tornadoes w/Hwy Dept. Tag" (English #TRA 0930) (Spanish) #TRA 1030, November 12, 1990 (Box 1252)
    - DUB NY Monsters Central Market. 103 minutes, August 26, 2005 (Box 1252)
    - Texas Tornados "Miller Lite Commercial" plus 2 "Don't Mess with Texa"s commercials one English, one Spanish (Box 1252)
    - Jazz Vatos Live! Includes a postcard on the event "20th Annual Regency Jazz Band's Holiday Saxophones - an evening dedicated to the memory of Randy Garibay" (Box 1252)
    - Ernie w/Big Band & music videos (Box 1252)
    - SDQ Doug Sahm Tex. Torn. TT Tx. Convention TT Nashville NOW SDQ ACL." (Box 1252)
    - Proclamation Ernie Durawa Day (Box 1252)
    - Austin Jazz Band Zilker Hillside Theatre (Box 1252)
    - Brook Mays Drum Clinic - Ernie Durawa, Aaron Lack" (Box 1252)
    - 63 minutes, April 18, 2004 (Box 1252)
    - Senate Master Sweden & SA (Box 1252)
    - Gruene 40 min Sweden 31 min Doug & Willie13 min at the Ritz (Box 1252)
    - Eureka Jazz Festival, 1995 (Box 1252)
    - The Full Moon Show # 6 "New Orleans" (Box 1252)
    - School of Conversation Tour 9/01 Holland Clarksville Jazz Fest '96 Blending music styles, 1996 (Box 1252)
    - Terry's Mega Guitar Benefit Concert, April 6, 1996 (Box 1252)
    - Texas Tornadoes Az. State Fair 80 min Ernie D, October 19, 1991 (Box 1252)
    - Nashiville NOW! w/Ernie Assorted Ernie videos Tornadoes, Hillbillies, etc. (Box 1252)